<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on dyve.net</title>
    <link>https://dyve.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on dyve.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 10:29:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dyve.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wake: 1997-2017</title>
      <link>https://dyve.net/post/the-wake-1997-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 10:29:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</author>
      <guid>https://dyve.net/post/the-wake-1997-2017/</guid>
      <description>In 1997 I started a website to learn HTML. It felt like I was kind of late to the party. Mosaic had already come and gone. Internet Explorer was the next big thing. I remember thinking about a subject for my website. I was an avid reader of Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s Sandman comics, and since these were quite popular online, I decided to make that my subject. The site went through some design iterations and internet addresses, before finding a permanent address: dyve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brand New Blog</title>
      <link>https://dyve.net/post/brand-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</author>
      <guid>https://dyve.net/post/brand-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>After the demise of Posterous in 2013, I moved my blog to Tumblr and mostly forgot about it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like investing time and energy in yet another platform that could be acquired and shut down. Also, Tumblr never felt right for what I wanted to do.
The past few years I have been playing with static site generators like Nikola. I liked their ideas and simplicity. A while ago I found the best static site generator I&amp;rsquo;d ever seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermoon, March 20 2011</title>
      <link>https://dyve.net/post/supermoon-march-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 07:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</author>
      <guid>https://dyve.net/post/supermoon-march-2011/</guid>
      <description>A picture of the supermoon we enjoyed in The Netherlands today.
I used a Nikon P5000 compact camera mounted on a Leica APO 77 Televid spotting scope. The scope is mean for birdwatching, but it&amp;rsquo;s not bad for an occasional look at the skies. The scope was set to 20x magnification, camera&amp;rsquo;s optical zoom varies per shot, as does shutter time and other settings (I tried to capture both the details of the moon&amp;rsquo;s surface as well as the stunning brightness of the supermoon, so I experimented).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hex Color Picker</title>
      <link>https://dyve.net/post/hex-color-picker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</author>
      <guid>https://dyve.net/post/hex-color-picker/</guid>
      <description>Hex Color Picker allows you to edit and view hexadecimal color codes in the standard Mac OS X color panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification Atlas of Birds of Aragon</title>
      <link>https://dyve.net/post/2010-08-30-identification-atlas-of-birds-of-aragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 09:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</author>
      <guid>https://dyve.net/post/2010-08-30-identification-atlas-of-birds-of-aragon/</guid>
      <description>The Identification Atlas of Birds of Aragon is an amazing collection of PDF&amp;rsquo;s (of up to 6MB in size) of various birds that can be found in Aragon, Spain. Very useful for birders that visit Europe. Great pictures of specific differences between species.
Thank you, Javier Blasco!
Update 2018-12-05: replaced dead links with working links</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of jQuery autocomplete</title>
      <link>https://dyve.net/post/a-brief-history-of-jquery-autocomplete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 06:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</author>
      <guid>https://dyve.net/post/a-brief-history-of-jquery-autocomplete/</guid>
      <description>Early 2005, I wrote what appears to be the first ever jQuery autocompleter. Several people used it, modified it, fixed bugs, made it better. Notably Dan G. Switzer. J&amp;ouml;rn Zaffaerer (who I met last year and is a very nice guy) did a complete rewrite, which depends on other jQuery plugins, and has a lot of added functionality. When I needed some modifications, I took Dan&amp;rsquo;s version of my original and did some slight modifications of my own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicking off</title>
      <link>https://dyve.net/post/kicking-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2007 09:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>dylan@dyve.net (Dylan Verheul)</author>
      <guid>https://dyve.net/post/kicking-off/</guid>
      <description>August 1 I will be switching jobs. This will mean that I am once more (among other things) a professional programmer. This time around the tools of the trade will be PHP, MySQL and JavaScript (with more than a touch of jQuery). Also, I&amp;rsquo;ll be switching from Windows to Mac OS X (actually, I&amp;rsquo;m typing this entry on my brand new MacBook Pro).
I thought this would be a good time to convert this site to a live blog once more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>